<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<nodes>
  <node>
    <Title>&lt;a href="/students/orientation/index.shtml"&gt;Online Orientation | Student Support &amp; Development&lt;/a&gt;</Title>
    <Featured-Image></Featured-Image>
    <Main-Content>&lt;h1 style="text-align: center;"&gt;Online Orientation&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h3 style="text-align: center;"&gt;&lt;strong style="font-size: 18px;"&gt;Welcome to DCU&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: center;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;img src="/sites/default/files/students_learning/DCU%20Glasnevin%20Campus.jpg" height="243" width="363"&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hello, and welcome to DCU's &lt;strong&gt;Online Orientation &lt;/strong&gt;Guide for your first year at university. Settling into university can be challenging on so many levels, so we are providing you with a step by step guide to the year ahead, which will make this transition much easier and make sure that you don't miss out on any key events / deadlines during your first year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On a weekly basis, we will highlight the important cut-off dates in the academic calendar, remind you of events taking place, which may be of benefit to your development as a student and provide you with a short 'check-list' to help you stay on track through the first year of your studies. Once you progress into Second Year, you will have become used to university life and will be well able to keep an eye on your progression yourself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Key events / dates each week will be marked with a &lt;img src="https://www4.dcu.ie/sites/default/files/students/images/lightbulb.jpg" height="26" width="18"&gt; to make it really easy for you to spot the 'must do' items. If you keep an eye on these, we assure you that you will find it much easier this coming year and that you will develop key skills, which will stand to you through life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Simply get into the habit of 'checking into' the &lt;strong&gt;Online Orientation&lt;/strong&gt; at the beginning of each week over the coming year – and avoid missing out on the key milestones in this crucial year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, get browsing and find out how DCU works and what you need to know during this important time.&lt;/p&gt;</Main-Content>
  </node>
  <node>
    <Title>&lt;a href="/students/orientation/orientationWeek5.shtml"&gt;Student Support &amp; Development - Online Orientation&lt;/a&gt;</Title>
    <Featured-Image></Featured-Image>
    <Main-Content>&lt;div class="orientation"&gt;&lt;div id="section_heading"&gt;&lt;h1 class="section_title"&gt;Online Orientation&lt;!-- SECTION HEADING ENDS --&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Week 5: 17th &amp;nbsp;– 21st October 2016&lt;!-- PAGE HEADING ENDS --&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div id="flash-carousel"&gt;&lt;img src="/sites/default/files/students_learning/Study.jpg" width="162" height="244"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="focus"&gt;&lt;img src="https://www4.dcu.ie/sites/default/files/students/images/lightbulb.jpg" alt="Focus on icon" id="bulb" width="26" height="30"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Focus this Week:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;ul id="num"&gt;&lt;li&gt;Writing Assignments&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Citing and Referencing&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Keeping the balance right - Mindfulness Stress Reduction Workshop&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;&amp;nbsp;Work through &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.library.dcu.ie/lets/index.htm"&gt;Module 4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; of the Library's LETS tutorial (LETSCite) - this will explain how to cite and reference correctly.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;If you have a submission date for a paper during Reading Week, ask your lecturer if you need to submit electronically or by hard copy. Find the 'submission box' in your School, if there is one.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Take the workshop on &lt;strong&gt;Assignment Writing.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong&gt;You will pick up some really good skills, which will make your first assignments easier to approach. Register&lt;strong&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.dcu.ie/students/events.shtml" target="_blank"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.dcu.ie/students/events.shtml" target="_blank"&gt;.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;As this is a key week in the academic year, take some time to reflect on your progress and how you are performing. Speak to your Personal Tutor, lecturers, Chairperson or somebody in the &lt;a href="https://www.dcu.ie/advice/index.shtml" target="_blank"&gt;Student Advice Centre&lt;/a&gt; if you have not settled in to DCU at this point.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Take part in the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www4.dcu.ie/students/counselling/mindfulness-lunchtime-course.shtml" target="_blank"&gt;Mindfulness Stress Reduction workshop series&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong&gt;and learn to manage your stress levels and increase concentration.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p&gt;Continue to use your &lt;strong&gt;Student Diary and&lt;a href="https://www4.dcu.ie/students/a-z-guide.shtml" target="_blank"&gt; online A-Z Guide&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;for hints, tips, contact details and explanations of DCU terms.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Citing &amp; Referencing:&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;It is really important that you acknowledge all sources of information used in your assignments correctly - failure to attribute&amp;nbsp;information to the correct source could be interpreted as &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www4.dcu.ie/students/az/plagiarism" target="_blank"&gt;plagiarism&lt;/a&gt;,&lt;/strong&gt; which&amp;nbsp;must be avoided at all costs, as it is a serious academic&amp;nbsp;offence. If you are required to use the Harvard Style of Referencing, which many of you will be, consult the online guide &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.dcu.ie/library/classes_and_tutorials/citing.shtml"&gt;'DCU Library Guide to Harvard Style of Citing &amp; Referencing'&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Remember to check the &lt;strong&gt;library website on your campus&lt;a href="http://www.library.dcu.ie/index.shtml"&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;for news about Citing and Referencing Workshops, which will take place around this time.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www4.dcu.ie/library/index.shtml" target="_blank"&gt;Glasnevin Library&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://leabharlann.spd.dcu.ie/" target="_blank"&gt;St Patricks Library&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;!-- CONTENTS END --&gt;&lt;!-- List of links --&gt;</Main-Content>
  </node>
  <node>
    <Title>&lt;a href="/students/orientation/orientationWeek2.shtml"&gt;Student Support &amp; Development - Online Orientation&lt;/a&gt;</Title>
    <Featured-Image></Featured-Image>
    <Main-Content>&lt;div class="orientation"&gt;&lt;div id="section_heading"&gt;&lt;h1 class="section_title"&gt;Online Orientation&lt;!-- SECTION HEADING ENDS --&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Week 2: 26th September - 30th September 2016&lt;!-- PAGE HEADING ENDS --&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Clubs &amp; Societies Week&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;img src="/sites/default/files/students_learning/Clubs%20and%20Socs.1.jpg" alt="chinese students" width="145" height="219"&gt;&lt;div class="focus"&gt;&lt;img src="https://www4.dcu.ie/sites/default/files/students/images/lightbulb.jpg" alt="Focus on icon" width="26" height="30" id="bulb"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Focus this Week:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;ul id="num"&gt;&lt;li&gt;Online Learning Resources&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Getting organised for study&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Managing your time&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Changing Optional Modules (26th September - 30th September)&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Making friends and settling in&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="clear"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;Take a look at the&lt;a href="http://www.dcu.ie/students/events.shtml" target="_blank"&gt; &lt;strong&gt;academic skills &lt;u&gt;workshops&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;while you have time over the first few weeks. Places are limited on these workshops, so book soon to reserve your place.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Take a look at the new online study skills resource on &lt;a href="https://loop.dcu.ie/login/index.php" target="_blank"&gt;Loop&lt;/a&gt;,&amp;nbsp;&lt;strong&gt;your DCU Virtual Learning Environment&lt;/strong&gt;, called &lt;strong&gt;skills4studycampus&lt;/strong&gt;. This is an interactive resource helping you with crucial skills such as note-taking, time management and academic writing. Do the various modules at your own pace and it will help you settle in much more quickly. Start this week!&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;If you haven't taken part in the Library Orientation Events for new students, do so this week. Call into the library on any of the campuses and see what is being arranged.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Put together a file for each module and get into the habit of taking the time to read through your notes after each lecture and fill in any gaps, while things are still fresh in your mind. You may consider doing this with a classmate or forming a study group.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Organise your week – time management is crucial to success at University and you need to start now, as the 12-week semester goes by very quickly. The &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.dcu.ie/students/advice/resources/health_wellbeing.shtml"&gt;U &amp; Your Mental and Physical Health &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;Booklet may help you. You can also pick up a hard copy of this booklet in the &lt;a href="https://www.dcu.ie/advice/index.shtml" target="_blank"&gt;Student Advice Centre&lt;/a&gt; in the Henry Grattan Building on the Glasnevin Campus or in C Block on the DCU St. Patrick's Campus.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;This week, you have the opportunity to&lt;strong&gt; change your optional modules&lt;/strong&gt;, if you are not happy with any of them (and if you have optional modules – not all programmes offer options in 1st Year). &lt;strong&gt;You can change your optional modules free of charge until this coming&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Friday, 30th September&lt;/strong&gt; - don't leave it until the last minute! Go to the 'change of mind' link on your Portal Page to make these changes. If you need advice on your module choice, speak to your Personal Tutor, Year Head or Chairperson.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Join a Club or Society&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;nbsp;this week on your campus – this is the best way of making friends and becoming integrated into university life.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p&gt;Employers tell us that they actively seek students who have a well-rounded experience at university and who show academic but also personal and professional ambition and excellence. Active participation in clubs and/or societies is one of the ways that you can differentiate yourself from others, when competing for jobs in the future. You will not only get to know other students but will develop skills such as teamwork, organisation, possibly leadership – in a completely supportive environment. The nature of the clubs and societies is very varied, so you will definitely find something which suits you.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Clubs &amp; Societies&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Outside lectures, Clubs and Societies are the heart and soul of university life. There are over 100 to choose from and they range from competitive sport to participation in new hobbies. You can join a club or society for €4.00 or you can try out a few classes in a new sport or hobby for a couple of weeks and join later. Don't miss this opportunity to become involved with all aspects of life in the University.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;There are a range of programmes on for all levels - take a look at what is being offered by the Sports Development Service &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.dcu.ie/studentsport/recreation.shtml"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;. For a full overview of clubs and societies at DCU, click &lt;a href="http://www.dcu.ie/studentsport/clubs.shtml" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;here&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;!-- CONTENTS END --&gt;&lt;!-- List of links --&gt;</Main-Content>
  </node>
  <node>
    <Title>&lt;a href="/students/orientation/orientationWeek3.shtml"&gt;Student Support &amp; Development - Online Orientation&lt;/a&gt;</Title>
    <Featured-Image></Featured-Image>
    <Main-Content>&lt;div class="orientation"&gt;&lt;h1 class="section_title"&gt;Online Orientation&lt;!-- SECTION HEADING ENDS --&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Week 3: 3rd - 6th October 2016&lt;!-- PAGE HEADING ENDS --&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;img src="/sites/default/files/students_learning/Library.1.jpg" width="247" height="227"&gt;&lt;div class="focus"&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;img src="https://www4.dcu.ie/sites/default/files/students/images/lightbulb.jpg" alt="Focus on icon" id="bulb" width="26" height="30"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Focus this Week:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;ul id="num"&gt;&lt;li&gt;Workshops&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Using the Library&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Understanding Loop&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Confirming your Programme Choice&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;&amp;nbsp;Take the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.library.dcu.ie/lets/index.htm"&gt;online library tutorial &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;(called LETS for the Glasnevin Campus), which explains how to get the best from the Glasnevin Campus Library. Call to the Library Information Desk on the Ground Floor if you need any information about using this facility.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Start becoming acquainted with &lt;strong&gt;Loop&lt;/strong&gt;, the DCU e-learning environment. If you are having difficulties, contact &lt;a href="http://www4.dcu.ie/iss/teach-learn-students/moodle.shtml"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;the Loop helpdesk &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;for assistance.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Take part in the&amp;nbsp; &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www4.dcu.ie/students/counselling/mindfulness-lunchtime-course.shtml" target="_blank"&gt;Mindfulness Stress Reduction workshop series&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong&gt;and learn to manage your stress levels and increase concentration.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Take part in the new '&lt;a href="https://www.dcu.ie/advice/pathways-to-success.shtml" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pathways to Success&lt;/strong&gt;'&lt;/a&gt; program.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Take a quiet evening to evaluate how you are getting on in your programme. If you are questioning your choice, speak to somebody to see what options are available to you. You can also pick up (in the Student Advice Centre, Glasnevin Campus) or download a copy of our booklet &lt;a href="https://www.dcu.ie/advice/resources-academic.shtml" target="_blank"&gt;'&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.dcu.ie/advice/resources-academic.shtml" target="_blank"&gt;Thinking of Changing Programme&lt;/a&gt;'&lt;/strong&gt;, which gives you the options. Drop into&lt;strong&gt; see a Student Adviser on your campus or&lt;/strong&gt; to find out who the best person to speak to is, mail &lt;a href="mailto:support.support@dcu.ie"&gt;support.support@dcu.ie&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Read your 'Settling In Guide' &lt;strong&gt;Booklet&lt;a href="/sites/default/files/students_advice/pdfs/SSD_Stepsguide_beginning_2013.pdf"&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;you received in your Orientation Pack, and you will find some easy ways of finding your place in the University.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p&gt;By Week 3 you will have an idea of where you are going, what you are doing and what your programme is like. For many of you, everything will be running smoothly and you will settle in with new friends and enjoy what you are studying. What if, however, you have niggling fears in the back of your mind? Perhaps the whole university experience feels a bit overwhelming at the moment? Are you worried that the programme is different to what you had expected it to be?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;What are my options if I am unhappy with my programme?&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;If you feel that the programme you have chosen is not for you, there is still time to change your mind. However, please think carefully about this. Keep in mind that the early stages of some programmes can be slow to gain momentum and, given a few weeks, things may look completely different. Before making any decisions about transferring programmes or withdrawing, make sure that you have looked for advice from your Chairperson, Personal Tutor, Year Head or the &lt;a href="https://www.dcu.ie/advice/index.shtml" target="_blank"&gt;Student Advice Centre&lt;/a&gt; Please note that your 'free fees' status (or grant) may be effected if you change programme. Useful fees information can be found &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="/sites/default/files/students_counselling/pdfs/Fees%20Information%20for%20Students%202014-2015.pdf"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Booklet&lt;strong&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://www.dcu.ie/advice/resources-academic.shtml" target="_blank"&gt;'Thinking of Changing Programme'&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;nbsp;gives you all of the available options in a clear format, should you be having doubts about your programme. Options may include transferring, deferring, withdrawing. You can download this booklet or pick up a hard copy, free of charge, in the &lt;a href="http://www.dcu.ie/advice/index.shtml" target="_blank"&gt;Student Advice Centre&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</Main-Content>
  </node>
  <node>
    <Title>&lt;a href="/students/orientation/orientationWeek4.shtml"&gt;Student Support &amp; Development - Online Orientation&lt;/a&gt;</Title>
    <Featured-Image></Featured-Image>
    <Main-Content>&lt;div class="orientation"&gt;&lt;h1 class="section_title"&gt;Online Orientation&lt;!-- SECTION HEADING ENDS --&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Week 4: 10th - 14th October 2016&lt;!-- PAGE HEADING ENDS --&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;img src="/sites/default/files/students_learning/Study.1.jpg" alt="Placeholder image" width="277" height="197"&gt;&lt;div class="focus"&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;img src="https://www4.dcu.ie/sites/default/files/students/images/lightbulb.jpg" alt="Focus on icon" id="bulb" width="26" height="30"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Focus this Week: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;ul id="num"&gt;&lt;li&gt;Getting down to study&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Improving your Reading and Note Taking Techniques&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Maths Support at DCU&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;&amp;nbsp;Take part in workshops - You will pick up some really good skills, which will make your first assignments easier to approach. Register &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www4.dcu.ie/students/events.shtml"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Take the online &lt;a href="https://www.dcu.ie/careers/about-pfs.shtml" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Learning Style Indicator&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, which will help you identify the ways you may learn best and make you a much more proficient learner. This is aimed at advanced learners and will be of benefit to you, no matter how well you think you know yourself.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong style="color: #ee062b;"&gt;Friday, 21st October&lt;/strong&gt; is the absolute final date for deferring your programme or withdrawing from the University.&amp;nbsp; If you are considering either of these options, call to the &lt;a href="https://www.dcu.ie/advice/index.shtml" target="_blank"&gt;Student Advice Centre &lt;/a&gt;well in advance of this date, and discuss the options.&amp;nbsp; If your miss this date, there are considerable financial consequences, so please take note of this deadline.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Now that you are beginning to be aware of the academic challenges of university, it is worth taking a look to see what supports are available:&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Look at the comprehensive information on academic skills development on the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://www4.dcu.ie/studentlearning/index.shtml"&gt;Student Learning&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; pages&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Visit the 'free' support sessions in the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.dcu.ie/maths/mlc/index.shtml"&gt;Maths Learning Centre&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; which is located in the Glasnevin Campus Library.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;!-- CONTENTS END --&gt;&lt;!-- List of links --&gt;</Main-Content>
  </node>
  <node>
    <Title>&lt;a href="/students/orientation/orientationWeek1.shtml"&gt;Student Support &amp; Development - Online Orientation&lt;/a&gt;</Title>
    <Featured-Image></Featured-Image>
    <Main-Content>&lt;div class="orientation"&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Online Orientation&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;div id="section_heading" class="orientation"&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Week 1: 19th September - 23rd September 2016&lt;!-- PAGE HEADING ENDS --&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;h2 class="orientation"&gt;Freshers' Week&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;img src="/sites/default/files/students_learning/DCU%20Glasnevin%20Campus.jpg" alt="Campus" height="182" width="273"&gt;&lt;div class="focus"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www4.dcu.ie/sites/default/files/students/images/lightbulb.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="https://www4.dcu.ie/sites/default/files/students/images/lightbulb.jpg" alt="Focus on icon" id="bulb" height="30" width="26"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Focus this Week:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;ul id="num"&gt;&lt;li&gt;Settling into your programme of study&amp;nbsp;&amp; making friends&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;&amp;nbsp;Make sure you have a &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.dcu.ie/timetables/search.shtml"&gt;full timetable&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; and keep an eye out for last minutes changes through the week&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Check the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www101.dcu.ie/registry/module_contents.php" target="_blank"&gt;academic structure of your programme&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, which provides a clear overview of each of the modules you will be taking this year&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Take part in the library orientation events organised this week - no need to book, just turn up. Full details&lt;a href="https://www.dcu.ie/library/index.shtml" target="_blank"&gt; &lt;/a&gt;on the websites at: &lt;a href="https://www.dcu.ie/library/index.shtml"&gt;DCU&amp;nbsp;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.dcu.ie/library/index.shtml"&gt;Glasnevin Campus Library&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://leabharlann.spd.dcu.ie/"&gt;DCU&amp;nbsp;St Patrick's Campus Library&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href="http://leabharlann.spd.dcu.ie/" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration: underline;"&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li type="_moz"&gt;Make sure you are registered correctly for all modules - this is your responsibility. Go to the Registry if you have any problems with your registration.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li type="_moz"&gt;Get to know some classmates – everyone in your group is new to DCU, so they will be looking to make new friends too.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is the week when all students are back on campus. There is always a brilliant buzz&amp;nbsp;around the University,&amp;nbsp;so enjoy it! The week will be filled with lectures, events and excitement around campus. There may also be fire drills, so remember to leave whatever building you are in immediately, should you hear the fire alarm.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Week 1&lt;/strong&gt; is the time to start good habits – and attending all lectures, tutorials and labs is one of the basics of university life. As many classes are not compulsory, it is up to you to turn up and make the most of each academic session. It is very easy to let this slip and soon you will find yourself left behind. A semester at DCU is only 12 weeks in duration – far too short to miss any of the classes in your programme.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;You will have plenty in common with other students in your class group, so if you have not met any like-minded people yet, make your way to your lecture hall now and start making friends! You will be provided with key information about your modules / recommended reading lists / assessments etc. during the first week. It's also a perfect time to get to know your lecturers before the hard work starts!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;To find out when and where your classes are, you will need your individual timetable. You will get this from your 'portal page'. You will need your 'username' and 'password', which you received when you picked up your student i.d. card last week,&amp;nbsp;to enter this site - check back on the documentation you received with your card and you will find it!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;!-- CONTENTS END --&gt;&lt;!-- List of links --&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</Main-Content>
  </node>
  <node>
    <Title>&lt;a href="/students/orientation/victor.shtml"&gt;Student Support &amp; Development - Online Orientation&lt;/a&gt;"</Title>
    <Featured-Image></Featured-Image>
    <Main-Content>p&gt;The Booklet&lt;strong&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://www.dcu.ie/advice/resources-academic.shtml" target="_blank"&gt;'Thinking of Changing Programme'&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;nbsp;gives you all of the available options in a clear format, should you be having doubts about your programme. Options may include transferring, deferring, withdrawing. You can download this booklet or pick up a hard copy, free of charge, in the &lt;a href="http://www.dcu.ie/advice/index.shtml" target="_blank"&gt;Student Advice Centre&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</Main-Content>
      </node>
</nodes>
